Guide to the New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement (LCLAA) Records WAG.328
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement (LCLAA) Records
2000-2014
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement
Ivany, Sonia
WAG.328
0.5 linear feet in one manuscript box
232.92 Gigabytes on 30 computer files
The NYC Chapter of the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement is a local chapter of the LCLAA national organization, which represents the interests of Latino/a trade unionists in the United States and Puerto Rico. The NYC LCLAA works with the labor movement, elected leaders, and community organizations on issues pertaining to advocacy, labor rights, and key issues for working families and the Latino/a community. The LCLAA works on issues such as immigration reform, voting rights and registration, social and economic justice, labor education, and youth outreach. This collection consists of materials created and collcted by the New York City LCLAA documenting their actvities to educate, organize and mobilize Latinos in the labor movement in an effort to positively impact workers' rights and their influence in the political process. Materials include photographs, union membership pamphlets, meeting agendas, programming flyers, informational brochures, invitations, press releases, digital video footage spanning from 2008-2014, and magazine and newspaper clippings documenting the outreach and organizing activities of the New York Labor Council for Latin American Advancement from approximately 2004-2014.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collcted by the New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement (LCLAA) documenting their actvities to educate, organize and mobilize Latinos in the labor movement in an effort to positively impact workers' rights and their influence in the political process. Materials in this collection include photographs, union membership pamphlets, meeting agendas, programming flyers, informational brochures, invitations, press releases, digital video footage from 2008-2014, and magazine and newspaper clippings documenting the organization's outreach and organizing activities from approximately 2004-2014. The video footage conists of panel talks, interviews, events, and rallies for May Day and the NY Dream Act. Also included in the collection are awards ceremony invitations, conference and membership reports, and correspondence to New York politicians including Charles Rangel and members of the LCLAA. In English, Spanish, and Chinese, these materials illustrate the events and activities of the New York City chapter, particularly in the areas of voter registration, membership and meetings, education and immigration reform, as well as direct action. Of possible interest are a members directory, flyers for meetings of the Women's Committee of the LCLAA, as well as materials on a rally in solidarity with workers in Puerto Rico.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Sonia Ivany (president), on behalf of the New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement, in 2011. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2011.147 and 2015.049.
An additional donation of videos was made by Sonia Ivany, President, NYC LCLAA, in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.036.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York City Chapter of the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement is a local chapter of the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement (LCLAA) national organization, which represents the interests of Latino/a trade unionists in the United States and Puerto Rico. The NYC LCLAA works with the labor movement, elected leaders, and community organizations on issues pertaining to advocacy, labor rights, and key issues for working families and the Latino/a community. The LCLAA works on issues such as immigration reform, voting rights and registration, social and economic justice, labor education, and youth outreach.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Labor unions; Latin Americans -- Employment -- United States; Latin Americans -- United States -- Social conditions; Labor Council for Latin American Advancement; New York City Labor Council for Latin American Advancement; Ivany, Sonia
- Brochures and Directories, 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Conference Programs, 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hunter College Interviews, 2012-07-11 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- Hunter College Program, 2012-07-11 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- Labor Celebration and Recognition Awards, 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
- Labor History, 2011-08 (E-records TW-WAG_328_2)
- Labor Women's Conference, 2013-2014 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA Fiesta Interviews, 2009-01 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA Annual Fiesta Program, 2009-01 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA Gala, 2008-05 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA Gala, 2010-05 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA History Archive, 2011-07-02 (E-records TW-WAG_328_2)
- LCLAA Murphy Institute 2013, 2013-2014 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- LCLAA Promotional Video, 2008-12-06 (E-records TW-WAG_328_2)
- LCLAA Promotional Video about Puerto Rico, 2009-10-19 (E-records TW-WAG_328_2)
- LCLAA Somos el Futuro Conference, 2013-2014 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- May Day March, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- May Day NYC, 2012-05 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- May Day Rally, 2010-05 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- May Day Rally, 2010-05-01 (E-records TW-WAG_328_2)
- Meetings and Events, 2000-2014 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
- Memebership Meeting Report: Muevete! El Futuro is Now, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- NYC LCLAA Only, 2012-05 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- PR Labor Breakfast, 2009-11 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- PR Press Conference NYC Leaders, 2009-11 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- Protests, 2009-11 (E-records TW_WAG_328_1)
- Photographs, 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Press Clippings, 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Puerto Rico Labor Unity Rally, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Puerto Rico Solidarity, 2009 October; TM_WAG_328_ER; 1.06 Gigabytes in one computer file (Item ER, E-records TW-WAG_328_2)